Guide to the Ralph Bunche papers
New York Public Library
Ralph Bunche papers
1922-1988
Sc MG 290
20652
Bunche, Ralph J. (Ralph Johnson), 1904-1971
Carnegie Corporation of New York
New York Public Library Stephen A. Schwarzman Building Fifth Avenue at 42nd Street New York, NY 10018-2788
64 boxes
Personal papers, family and general correspondence, writings, field notes and research materials, working papers, office files and printed matter documenting Ralph Bunche's personal life and professional career, from his enrollment at the University of California to his retirement in 1971.
Ralph Johnson Bunche began his career as an educator and a political scientist, and later joined the United Nations, serving for the last twenty years of his life as a special assistant to the General Secretary of that world body.
Born in 1904 of a working class family in Detroit, Michigan, Bunche went to live with his maternal grandmother in Los Angeles, California, after the death of his mother in 1917. He graduated from Jefferson High School in 1921, the University of California at Los Angeles in 1927 and the Harvard Graduate School in 1928. In 1929 he was awarded the Ozias Goodwin Memorial Fellowship at Harvard. His doctoral dissertation “French Administration in Togoland and Dahomey” received the Toppan Prize in 1934. Bunche conducted post-doctoral work in anthropology and colonial policy at Northwestern University in 1936, the London School of Economics in 1937 and the University of Capetown, South Africa, in 1938. He was a member of Phi Beta Kappa.
Bunche met Ruth Harris in Washington, D.C. at the start of his career at Howard University in 1928. They married in 1930. Born in Montgomery, Ala. in 1906 and the youngest of ten children, she graduated from Alabama State Normal and the Minor Normal School in Washington, D.C. where she worked as a teacher in the city's public school. Her father, Charles Harris, was the chief mailing clerk and a prominent civic leader in Montgomery. The Bunche couple had three children: Joan, Jane and Ralph, Jr.
Ralph Bunche joined the staff of Howard University in 1928, first as a lecturer and later as the chairman of the Department of Political Science. While at Howard, he organized a series of conferences on the problems of African-American communities in the United States. He joined various committees protesting discrimination by department stores and theaters, and organized his students to join picket lines in Washington, D.C. In 1932, Bunche traveled to West and North Africa on a Rosenwald Fellowship to survey French colonial administration. His pamphlet “A World View of Peace” was published in 1936. The same year, he received a two year Social Science Research Council Fellowship for field and research work in Africa and Europe.
Bunche took a leave of absence from Howard University in 1938 and joined the staff of the Carnegie Corporation in conducting and organizing a comprehensive survey of the social, political and economic status of blacks in the United States. Entitled “The Negro in America” and also known as the “Carnegie-Myrdal Study,” the survey was directed by the Swedish sociologist Gunnar Myrdal, and was based on the field work and the extensive research memoranda prepared by a staff of scholars and collaborators. In addition to coordinating various administrative aspects of the project, Bunche conducted several field trips in the South in 1939 and was the author of four sizable research memoranda: “A Brief and Tentative Analysis of Negro Leadership,” “Conceptions and Ideologies of the Negro Problem,” “The Political Status of the Negro” and “The Programs, Ideologies, Tactics and Achievements of Negro Betterment and Interracial Organizations.” These works are quoted extensively in Myrdal's American Dilemma(Harper & Brothers, 1944).
After the entrance of the United States in the Second World War, Bunche accepted a temporary assignment at the State Department, working first as a Senior Research Analyst in the Office of Strategic Services and, in 1944, as an area specialist for Africa and dependent territories. He became a member of the U.S. delegation at the founding of the United Nations in 1945, serving consecutively as Acting Chief of the Division of Dependent Area Affairs, Commissioner of the Anglo-American Caribbean Commission and, in 1946, as Director of the Division of Trusteeship.
Bunche joined the Permanent Secretariat of the United Nations in 1948 with the title of Principal Director of the Trusteeship Council. Known also as Committee Four of the General Assembly, the Council supervised the administration of colonial territories formerly belonging to Germany. These territories included French and British Togoland, the French and British Cameroons, the Belgian Congo, Ruanda-Urundi, New Guinea and Western Samoa. He was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize for his mediation of the Armistice Agreement between Israel and the Arab states in 1948, and was also credited for his role in organizing the U.N. Green Berets. He also played a major role in the day to day work of the organization, and enjoyed a wide reputation for his integrity, his commitment to world peace and his gift as a negotiator and administrator. Gravely ill toward the end of his life, Ralph Bunche retired from the United Nations in 1971, the year of his death.
Ralph Bunche enjoyed wide prominence and respect both as a scholar and statesman. A political moderate, he believed in petitioning government for justice but did not hesitate to march in protest when all else failed. During the 1960s, however, he came under attack for his apparent lack of support and identification with the politics of protest and direct action advocated by the civil rights movement of that era. He was also criticized for his role in the Congo after the failure of the U.N. peacekeeping force in preventing the overthrow and the assassination of Patrice Lumumba. Bunche is honored today, nonetheless, as an outstanding world leader and as a role model in the African American community.
The Ralph Bunche Papers document Bunche's personal life and professional career, from his enrollment at the University of California to his retirement in 1971. They have been divided into the following series: FAMILY PAPERS, comprising personal and biographical materials on Ralph and Ruth Bunche; CORRESPONDENCE, both family and general; ADDRESSES, ARTICLES AND ESSAYS; the HOWARD UNIVERSITY files, comprising administrative and academic materials; the SOUTH AFRICA RESEARCH TRIP in 1937; writings and research materials for the CARNEGIE-MYRDAL STUDY; working papers, mimeographed reports and printed matter relating to the United Nations' TRUSTEESHIP COUNCIL; AWARDS, MEMBERSHIPS AND TRIBUTES; SCRAPBOOKS; PRINTED MATTER AND CLIPPINGS.
I. Family papers; II. Correspondence; III. Writings; IV. Howard University; V. South Africa research trip; VI. Carnegie-Myrdal Study; VII. United Nations Trusteeship Council; VIII. Awards, membership and tributes; IX. Scrapbooks; X. Printed matter
Gift of the Bunche Family, 1990.
SCM 90-1
SCM 90-99
The following items were removed from:
Name of Collection: Ralph Bunche Papers
Accession Numbers: SCM 90-1
SCM 90-99
Donor: Ms. Joan Bunche
Date received: 1990
Date transferred: 1990, 1991.
The item(s) listed below have been sent to the division indicated, either to be retained or disposed of there. Any items that should receive special disposition are clearly marked.
Azikiwe, Nnamdi, 1904-1996; Bernadotte, Folke, 1895-1948; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942; Bostic, Franklin; Bunche, Joan; Bunche, Olive Johnson; Bunche, Ralph J. (Ralph Johnson), 1904-1971; Bunche, Ruth Harris; Cayton, Horace; Davis, E. P; Dorsey, Emmett; Filmer, Robert, Sir, d. 1653; Herskovits, Melville J. (Melville Jean), 1895-1963; Jackson, James; Jackson, Whilhelmina; Johnson, Charles Spurgeon, 1893-1956; Johnson, Ethel; Johnson, Guion Griffis, 1900-1989; Johnson, Guy Benton, 1901-1991; Johnson, Nellie Millie; Jones, Butler A; Keppel, Frederick P. (Frederick Paul), 1875-1943; Locke, Alain LeRoy, 1886-1954; Makonnen, T. R; Myrdal, Alva, 1902-1986; Myrdal, Gunnar, 1898-1987; Norgren, Paul H. (Paul Herbert); Padmore, George, 1902-1959; Pierce, Jane Bunche; Robinson, Grace Bunche; Sterner, Richard Mauritz Edvard, 1901-; Stoney, George; Stouffer, Samuel A., 1900-1960; Thant, U, 1909-1974; Thompson, Charles H; Urquhart, Brian; White, Walter Francis, 1893-1955; Wilkerson, Doxey Alphonso, 1905-1993; Williams, Eric Eustace, 1911-1981; Bunch family; Carnegie Corporation of New York; Harvard College (1780- ). Class of 1928; Harvard University; Howard University; Howard University. Dept. of Political Science; International African Service Bureau; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; Pan African Federation Organization; United Nations; United Nations Operation in the Congo; United Nations. General Assembly. Special Committee on Palestine; United Nations. Special Unit on Palestinian Rights; United Nations. Trusteeship Council; African American college teachers; African American leadership; African American teachers; African American universities and colleges; African Americans -- Civil rights; African Americans -- Economic conditions; African Americans -- Legal status, laws, etc; African Americans -- Segregation -- Southern States; African Americans -- Social conditions; African Americans -- Study and teaching; Arab-Israeli conflict; Black author; Colonies -- Africa; Decolonization; Discrimination -- United States; International trusteeships; Jewish-Arab relations -- History -- 1917-1948; Mandates -- Cameroon; Mandates -- Palestine; Mediation, International; Nobel Prizes; Pacific settlement of international disputes; Pan-Africanism; Political science -- Study and teaching; Political scientists in government; Spingarn Medal; Universities and colleges, Black; Voting -- United States; Congo (Democratic Republic) -- History -- Civil War, 1960-1965; France -- Colonies -- Administration; Israel -- Politics and government; Palestine -- History -- Partition, 1947; Palestine -- Politics and government -- 1917-1948; South Africa -- Economic conditions -- 1918-1961; South Africa -- Politics and government -- 1909-1948; South Africa -- Race relations; South Africa -- Social conditions; Southern States -- Race relations; United States -- Ethnic relations; United States -- Race relations
- Family Papers, 1922-1988
  FAMILY PAPERS (1922-1988) comprise personal papers of Ralph and Ruth Harris Bunche. The Ralph Bunche subseries includes educational, medical and financial papers, passports, personal and family documents. The Ruth Harris Bunche subseries consists of general and professional correspondence, speeches and miscellaneous writings, certificates and awards, scrapbooks and printed matter. The correspondence reflects her contributions to various benefits, charities and social activities, sponsored in many cases by wives of influential men such as David Rockefeller, Walter White, Vladimir Horowitz, Count Bernadotte and Roy Wilkins. Other noted correspondents include Martin Luther King, Jr., Bayard Rustin, Eubie Blake, Marian Anderson, Edward Koch, Irving Berlin, Jeane Kirkpatrick and George Bush. Mrs. Bunche served as a New York State delegate to the White House Conference on Education in 1955. She participated, along with her husband, in the March on Washington in 1963.
  - Ralph J. Bunche
    - Address and date books (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Educational -- Valedictory, 1928, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Jefferson High School (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - University of California at Los Angeles (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
    - Harvard University (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
    - Financial (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
    - Funeral (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Household furnishing (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Johnson family (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Last will and testament (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Medical (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Personal effects (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Travel (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Travel and speaking engagements (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - U.C.L.A. Southern Branch, The SouthernCampus, 1927; 2 volumes
    - Passports, (15), 1932-1965
    - Jefferson High School and University of California publications.
  - Ruth Harris Bunche
    - Speeches and miscellaneous writings (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Address and note books (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Certificates and awards (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Letters sent (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Letters received, to, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Letters received, 1972-1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Educational and professional activities (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Family insurance (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Legal (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
    - Memoirs (shorthand notes) (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Memorial tributes (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Passports and miscellaneous items (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Printed matter (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Christmas card lists (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Guest book, 1952-1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Guest book, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Funeral book (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Receptions (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Plaques
- Correspondence, 1929-1971
  The CORRESPONDENCE series (1929-1971) is divided into Family and General Correspondence
  - Family correspondence
    The subseries consists of letters exchanged between Ralph Bunche and his wife from 1929 to 1944, letters from his aunts Nelle and Ethel Johnson, his sister Grace Robinson, his mother Olive, correspondence with his children, and occasional correspondence between the Bunche household and the Harris, Johnson and Taylor families.
    - Ralph Bunche to Ruth Bunche
      - 1929 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - 1930 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - 1930 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - 1932 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - 1933 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - 1934-1941 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - n.d (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Postcards, telegrams and fragments (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Ralph Bunche to his children (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Ruth Bunche to Ralph Bunche
      - 1929 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - 1929 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - 1930 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - 1930 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - 1932-1933 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - 1936-1944 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - n.d (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Postcards, telegrams and fragments. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Olive Johnson Bunche (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Grace Bunche Robinson (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Nelle (Nellie Millie) Johnson (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Nelle (Nellie Millie) Johnson (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Ethel Johnson (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Joan Bunche (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Jane Bunche Pierce (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Ralph Bunche, Jr. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Ralph Bunche, Jr. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Johnson family (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Harris family (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Harris family (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Pierce family (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Taylor family (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Alton, Ill. relatives (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Miss Houston (housekeeper) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - re “Lady,” (family pet) (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence
    General Correspondence consists of three separate files: correspondence from his residency in London in 1937; correspondence relating to his retirement in 1971; and occasional correspondence between 1928 and 1971. Noted correspondents include Walter White, Alain Locke, George Padmore, T.R. Makonnen and Eric Williams.
    - 1928-1935 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Alain Locke, 1931-1932, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - 1937 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - 1937 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Walter White, 1939-1940 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - 1938-1972 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Esquire Magazine Award (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Retirement, A-F, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Retirement, G-M, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Retirement, N-Z, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Ralph Bunche's death, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Funeral arrangements, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Condolences, U. Thant, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Condolences, letters received, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Condolences, letters received, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Addresses, Articles and Essays, 1928-1969
  ADDRESSES, ARTICLES AND ESSAYS(1928-1969) are divided into two subseries: Conferences and Academic Writings and Addresses and Articles.
  - Conferences and Academic Writings
    The first subseries consists primarily of essays, articles and reviews written by Bunche, in addition to research notes and typescripts of his master's thesis “The Political Theory of Sir Robert Filmer” and his doctoral dissertation “French Administration in Togoland and Dahomey.”
    - Articles and reviews (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Articles and essays (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - “Political Theory of Sir Robert Filmer”
      - Typescript (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Research notes (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - “French Administration in Togoland and Dahomey” (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Seminar on the “Contribution of Gandhian Outlook and Techniques to the Solution of Tensions Between and Within Nations,” New Delhi, India, January 1953
      - Correspondence and program (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Address by Ralph Bunche (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Summary of discussions (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Verbatim records (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Addresses and Articles
    Addresses and Articles consist of files of Bunche's handwritten and typescript articles and speeches, with attachments. Spanning from 1951 to 1969, they are arranged chronologically, and alphabetically therein. Addressed mainly to academic and university audiences, and to civic and international gatherings, they deal with issues of world peace and his role at the United Nations. Also included are eulogies, television interviews and acceptance speeches for prizes, awards and honorary degrees conferred on him. Other writings by Bunche are located in the Carnegie-Myrdal series.
    - 1950 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Nobel Peace Prize (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 1951
      - A-H (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - I-Q (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - R-Z (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - 1952
      - A-O (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - P-Z (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - 1953 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - 1954
      - A-H (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - I-Z (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - 1955 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - 1956
      - A-I (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - J-Z (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - 1957 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - 1958 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - 1959
      - A-S (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - T-Z (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - 1960
      - A-R (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - S-Z (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - 1961 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - 1962 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - 1963
      - A-Q (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - R-Z (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - 1964 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - 1965 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - 1966 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - 1967
      - Bombay, India (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - The Hill School (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - International House, January (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Dayton Beach Open Forum, Feb. 6 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Radcliffe Club of New York, Feb. 15 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Marble Collegiate Church, Feb. 19 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Yale Political Union, Feb. 21 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Temple Emanu-El, Dallas, Mar. 2 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Texas Technical College, Mar. 3 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Gridiron Club Dinner, Mar. 11 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - NBC-TV “Today” Show, Mar. 21 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Columbia University School of International Affairs, Mar. 26 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Foreign Policy Association, Apr. 4 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - University of Chicago, Apr. 6 (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - University of Nebraska, Apr. 26 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Queens County Bar Association, May 4 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - NAACP Legal Defense Fund, May 17 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - U.N. International School, May 24 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Pacem In Terris, Geneva, May (Box 17, Folder 17)
        (cancelled)
      - Pacem In Terris, Geneva, May (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Deutscher Evangelisher, Germany, Jun. 25 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Expo Montreal, '67; Aug (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Purdue University, Oct (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Charlotte-Mecklenburg Schools, Nov. 4 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Pugwash Conference (17th), Sweden (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - University of California at Los Angeles (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - 1968
      - World Affairs Council, CA., Feb. 20 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - California State College, Feb (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Ohio State University, Mar. 5 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Old First Church, Springfield, MA., Mar. 20 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Aruba, (cancelled), Mar (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - McCall Forum on Black Awareness, Jun. 13 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Institute of World Affairs, Aug. 5 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - University of Nebraska, Jun. 1 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Queensboro Community Coll., NY, Jun. 18 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Pugwash Conference, 18th), Sep (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - UCLA Alumni Magazine, Oct (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Esquire Magazine Round Table, Dec. 10 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - 1969
      - Alfafa Club Dinner, Jan (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Apollo 8 Astronauts Visit U.N., Jan (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Tryvie Lie Funeral, Jan (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - St. Paul School, Feb (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - UCLA, Associated Students Speakers Program, Feb (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - Virginia Polytechnic Inst., Feb (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - Compton College, Feb (Box 19, Folder 16)
      - R.F. Kennedy School, Compton, CA (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - NBC-TV “Today” Show, Feb (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - D. Eisenhower Funeral, Mar (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Rockefeller Project, Mar (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Ralph Bunche, Jr. Graduation, Fort Benning, GA, Apr (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Rockefeller Project, Apr (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - University of Detroit, Apr (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Greenwich Fair Housing, CT, May (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Temple University, May (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Occidental College, Los Angeles, CA, May (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - UCLA, Bunche Hall Dedication (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Autobiographical, Jun. 1 (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Teachers Remembrance Day, Jun. 1 (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - UCLA, 50th Anniversary Dedication, May (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Pi Sigma Alpha Banquet, May (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Honolulu, May (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Readers' Digest article, Jun (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - U.N. Association of the U.S.A., Jun (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - East-West Conference, Hawaii, Jul (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - East-West Philosophers Conference, Hawaii, Jul (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - East-West Philosophers Conf., Jul (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Nobel Symposium, Sep (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Pugwash Conference, 19th), Dec (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Pugwash Conference, 19th), Dec (Box 22, Folder 2)
- South Africa Trip, 1937
  The SOUTH AFRICA RESEARCH TRIP series (1937) consists of letters of recommendation, correspondence with the United States Department of State, South African officials and the Rosenwald Fund, in addition to field notes, legal documents and printed matter.
  - Main file (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, General (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Social Science Research Council (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Letters of recommendation (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Letters of recommendation, sealed copies (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Letters of recommendation, pre 1937 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Reports (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Notes, addresses and memoranda (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Income, acknowledgements, receipts (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Travel arrangements (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Expenses (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Equipment (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Foreign Policy Association (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - L-P (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - M (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - T (Box 23, Folder 16)
- Howard University, 1928-1941